# Luis Herrera

#### Colombia



linkedin.com/in/lh1008



https://github.com/lh1008



1209@holbertonschool.com



3057128788

### Summary

Cryptocurrency privacy-focused Monero (XMR) enthusiast. Focused in open-source software GNU/Linux operating systems since 2016.

Studied Software Engineering foundations at Holberton School Colombia with a high passion for blockchain technology. Entrepreneur, adventurer, and eager to develop code for our world.

Experience in C, Python, and JavaScript programming languages, hand-coded HTML and CSS with MySQL database integration.

### **Experience**



#### \Omega Communication Group Coordinator (Volunteer)

Monero

Jul 2018 - Present (2 years 1 month +)

Workgroup production coordinator. Organize translators, transcriptionist's workload and publish final content throughout the community.

# Software Engineer

**Holberton School** 

Sep 2019 - Jun 2020 (10 months)

Full-time programmer. Experience with C, Python, and Javascript programming languages, and database management with MySQL (SQLalchemy).

During this project, we developed 3 low-level C programming & algorithms projects, 4 higher level Python and JavaScript programming projects, 8 system engineering DevOps projects, a Social Media build profile, and our own portfolio project that was live transmitted through Facebook live. We also used MySQL as relational database management systems, SQLalchemy, RESTful, and JavaScript APIs and deployed virtual servers using Docker and hardware servers.

We also developed our soft skills by doing every day stand-ups where we had to speak about a specific topic that gave us the tools to speak in public. Made every 8-15 days face-to-face or online mock interviews to test our interview abilities and put our peers to the test. We had a great working environment where we had to whiteboard code and test our skills to communicate what we were coding with a 60 weekly/hours of workload.

## ■ Database Analyst

**EMCALI - Telecomunicaciones** 

Sep 2016 - Feb 2018 (1 year 6 months)

Database analyst. I also did the Geographic Information System software (GEOVISOR/MapInfo) colleagues training. My main task was to maintain the database information updated using the integrated OPEN-SmartFlex software. Databases were handled using Microsoft Excel crossed-based between different government official databases (FOSYGA, RUAF, DIAN, and PROCURADURIA).

## **Business Development Administrator**

**Productos Vrinda** 

Feb 2013 - May 2016 (3 years 4 months)

Production and service manager. My responsibilities were to cover the customer service area, staff planning, purchase, storage, and sales. I had to contact suppliers, make the financial accounting control, have resource optimization, and comply with quality standards and regulations of the food and beverage sector.

#### Georeferencer

Servinformación

Feb 2010 - Feb 2013 (3 years 1 month)

My task was to homologate the national property number in the company's databases to the EMCALI subscriber. I also made routing fieldwork through Geographic Information Systems (GIS). Geographic software layer control, collector supervisor, and location coordinates updates. Software: MapInfo, Excel, Access.

### Commercial Director

Chef en tu Casa

2012 - 2012 (1 year)

Logistics, purchases, accounting, and cash management.

### ■ CSR

Kimeline

Dec 2010 - Mar 2011 (4 months)

**Customer Service Representative** 

#### **Education**

### Holberton School

Software Engineer, Programming

2019 - 2021

# Udemy Academy

Web Designer, Web Development

2017 - 2018

Design, update, and web structure development using HTML and CSS. SEO positioning, CSS and 3D animations. Domain hosting and account management.

# Economics, Economy

2006 - 2017

The economics career analyzes the individual and his social-economic behavior. The implementation of econometric analysis is essential for understanding social organization.

### **Licenses & Certifications**

#### Berlitz Proficiency Test - BERLITZ

Issued Dec 2012 - Expires Dec 2014

#### **Skills**

English • Customer Service • Team Leadership • MapInfo Professional • C (Programming Language) • Python (Programming Language) • JavaScript • MySQL • Programming • Open Source Software